SubHD字幕网 业余渣翻人
十环的传说
The legend of the ten rings
已经流传了上千年
has been told for thousands of years.
不论 这个故事如何演变
Every generation, the story grows.
它的主人公永远都是同一个人
But at its centre there is always one man.
有人说他的十环是火山口里捡来的 还有人说是墓穴里盗来的
Some say he found the rings in a crater or stole them from a tomb.
它们给了他神一般的力量
They gave him the strength of a god,
也赋予了他长生不老的魔法
and the gift of eternal life.
他本可借这十环之力惩恶扬善
He could have used them for good.
但他想要的
But all he wanted...
只有征服
was power.
他打造了一支十环军团
He called his army The Ten Rings.
千百年来 他们扫荡了世界的每个角落
Over the centuries, they spread into every corner of the world.
他们潜伏于暗中
They moved in the shadows...
颠覆各方政权
Toppled governments...
也改写了历史
And changed the course of history.
凭借着十环之力 他早已称霸千年
He chased money and power for a thousand years.
但他却还不满足
But he still wanted more.
你听说过塔罗的传说吗?
Have you heard the legend of Ta Lo?
一个隐世的村庄 在那里 神者的功法代代相传
A hidden village with mythical creatures and ancient magic.
传说中的神兽和古老的法术还都存在
Where people practise a martial arts style from the gods.
我要找到这个地方
I want to find it.
明白 我这就派侦察队去一探究竟
Of course. I'll send a scout to explore the area,
然后 有消息立马跟您汇报
and come back with more information.
我们现在就去
I want to go now.
竹林子...
The forest...
好像在动...
...is moving.
这世上再也没有可以让他征服的地方了
He had nothing left on Earth to conquer.
于是 他找上了我的家乡
That's when he came for my home.
塔罗的入口在哪?
Where's the entrance to Ta Lo?
我们村庄不欢迎你
You're not welcome in our village.
你好像不知道我是谁
You don't know who you're talking to.
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
走吧 不要自找麻烦
Turn around now, and I won't have to hurt you.
就这点本事？
Is that all?
那是我第一次见到你的父亲
That was the first time I met your father.
我从没想过自己会为他动心
He was the last person I thought I'd fall for.
但爱总是自有安排
But love had other plans.
尚气
Shang Chi,
十环的传说啊 讲都讲不完
there's much more to know about the legend of the rings,
等你长大了 自然就会了解的
but you'll learn about that when you're older.
可爸爸的十环那么厉害 你是怎么打败他的
If Dad's rings were so powerful, how did you beat him?
妈妈的故乡塔罗 有一个神龙
Where I'm from, we are empowered by
它是我们的保护神 它将魔法赋予在了我们每个人身上
The magic of the Great Protector.
等你领悟了神龙之心
When you have the heart of our dragon,
你就可以做很多了不起的事情
you can do some amazing things.
那你现在还有魔法吗？
Can you still do those things?
妈妈离开的时候啊 把魔法还给了神龙
I left those powers in Ta Lo with our dragon,
但是妈妈得到的更宝贵
but what I got in return is so much better.
这个给你
I want you to have this.
如果你有一天迷路了
Whenever you feel lost,
它会帮你找到回家的路
this will help you find your way home.
记住了吗?
Can you remember that?
现在
你好,先生,
Hello, sir,
欢迎来到费尔蒙特……
welcome to the Fairmont...
我来开车
I'm driving.
不,你不是……凯蒂
No, you're not... Katy.
嘿 嘿 回来
Hey, hey, get back here.
把钥匙给我
Give me the key.
请把门打开
Please open the door.
哦,我的天
Oh, my God.
下车  你给我上车!
Get out.   You get in!
听着 如果这车有什么闪失
Look, if happens to this thing,
我们会失业的
we're gonna be jobless
那我们的余生都要背负债务
and in debt for the rest of our lives.
噢 快上来吧 这辆车不会有事的
Oh, come on. Nothing's gonna happen to this car.
我是亚洲版的杰夫·戈登
I'm the Asian Jeff Gordon.
我不知道那是谁
I don't know who that is.
在他纳斯卡赛车职业生涯中 赢得最多冠军那位
Most career wins in all of NASCAR history?
请下车
Please get out of the car.
肖恩,
Shaun,
我们做了十年的朋友 好吗?
we've been friends for 10 years, okay?
你知道我不是白痴
You know I'm not an idiot.
快上车 我会慢慢开的
Please, get in. I'll go slow.
凯蒂 小心...
Katy, watch the...
在我高中认识她的第一天
I knew Katy was trouble
我就知道凯蒂是个麻烦精了
the first day we met in high school.
由于种种原因
I was getting picked on a lot,
我经常被欺负 我们都是
for all the reasons we all get picked on a lot.
而且 我刚搬到美国
Plus, I had just moved to the US,
所以我的英语很糟糕
so I was struggling with my English,
有一天我在去吃午饭的路上
and I was on my way to lunch one day
一个身材是我两倍的人
when this guy who was like twice my size
冲着我大喊大叫
yells at me from down the hall,
“过得怎么样 江南Style?”
"What's up, Gangnam Style?"
于是我吼道 “我不是韩国人 白痴 ”
So I yelled back, "I'm not Korean, idiot."
当我转过街角
And I turn the corner,
我看到这个人放下了背包
and I see this guy drop his backpack,
他看起来愤怒极了
he's getting all up in his face...
就在他要出手的时候
And right before he was about to throw the first punch,
凯蒂突然冒了出来
Katy comes out of nowhere,
走到我们中间 大声唱着歌词
steps right between us and starts screaming the lyrics
加州旅馆
to Hotel California.
什么?
What?
这就是困惑艺术 对愚蠢的人很有效
It's the art of confusion. Works great on stupid people.
我们就是这样认识的
And that's how we met.
然后我把他拉进了停车场…
Then I pulled him into the parking lot...
这时她跟我讲
At which point she revealed
她还偷了那人野马车的钥匙
that she had also swiped the keys to the guy's Mustang.
是啊 我们还上街区去兜风了
Yeah, we went on a little joyride around the block.
你妻子也在车里
And your wife was in the car, too.
是真的 你也在车上  什么?
That's true. You were.   What?
我只是在后座上坐着
I was just in the back seat.
那也是车的一部分
That's a part of the car.
确实是车的一部分
That's still a part of the car.
你怎么从没告诉过我这个故事?
How have you never told me this story?
在她成为律师之前
You know, before she was a lawyer,
你的女朋友很狂野
your girl was pretty wild.
哦!发生了什么事了?
Oh! What happened?
我成长了
I grew up.
那是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
对啊 什么意思?
Yeah, what's that supposed to mean?
也许是到了
That maybe there's a point
停止飙车那个时候了
where you're supposed to stop going on joyrides
该去开始考虑发挥自己的潜能了
and start thinking about living up to your potential.
你在开玩笑吧 苏
Please tell me you're kidding, Soo.
听着
Look,
我们现在生活在一个
we're now living in a world
可能某个时候
where at any moment
地球上的人就会消失一半的世界
half the population can just disappear.
生命太短暂 太脆弱
Life's too short and too fragile.
凯蒂 你这泊车司机
Katy, you're a valet driver
可是有伯克利荣誉学位的
with an honours degree from Berkeley,
而肖恩你会说四种语言
and Shaun can speak, like, four languages.
你们一直都是我认识的最有才华的人
You've always been the most talented people I know.
我只是不明白你们为什么那么害怕
I just don't get why you're scared
把才华用在严肃的事情上
to actually use it for something serious.
哇
Wow.
你说话跟我妈一样 你穿得...
You sound like my mom. You also...
穿得也和她有点像
dress like her a little bit, too.
哪买来的 Talbots?
Where's this from, Talbots?
Talbots是一个来自美国拥有60年经营历史的知名服装品牌
我们不是在逃避大人生活
We're not running from adulthood.
拥有自己喜欢的工作感觉不是挺好的吗？
How is it running to have jobs that you actually like?
是啊 这根本说不通啊
Yeah, that doesn't even make any sense.
你觉得代客泊车容易吗?
Did you think valet parking is easy?
我觉得它是最具挑战性的工作了
It's like the most challenging job ever.
你需要有人际交往能力 驾驶技能……
You need people skills, driving skills...
苏 甚至不能直直地停车
Soo can't even parallel park.
好了 快到午夜了 我们还要上早班
Well, it's almost midnight. We got the early shift.
该有责任地去睡觉了
Should probably be responsible, go to sleep.
是啊 我们也可以有责任 我们可以做到
Yeah, we can be responsible. We can do that.
还是说……
Or...
Over, sideways and under on a...
电影阿拉丁插曲  A Whole New World
Lil Nas X   Old Town Road
Take my horse to the old town road
I'm gonna
Close my eyes
Aerosmith  I Don't Want to Miss a Thing
I don't wanna...
早上好,陈太太
Morning, Mrs Chen.
她还没准备好
She's not ready yet.
你等的时候来喝点咖啡
Come have some joe while you wait.
凯蒂 肖恩到了
Katy, Shaun's here.
知道了 妈妈 马上就来
Yeah, Mom, be there in a minute.
瑞华
Ruihua,
你应该帮你爸爸进货的
you're supposed to be helping your dad stock the shop.
妈妈 我饿着肚子没法工作 我的腿会抽筋
Mom, I can't work on an empty stomach, my legs get crampy.
也许肖恩能帮他
Maybe Shaun can help him
而不是每天来吃我们的食物
instead of just showing up every day to eat our food.
我很乐意帮忙
I'm happy to help.
不 这是瑞华的工作 让他去吧
No, it's Ruihua's job, let him do it.
外婆
Waipo.
这是外公的座位
That seat's for Waigong.
哦,不好意思
Oh, sorry.
今年清明节 我准备给他 他最喜欢的东西
He's getting all his favourite things this year for the Day of the Dead.
你确定阴间
Are you sure that Waigong's allowed to take
会给外公带上
Funyuns and cigarettes
洋葱圈和香烟吗？
back to the afterlife?
他什么都可以收
He can take anything.
去年我在他的坟前上放了一瓶白酒…
Last year I put a bottle of whisky on his grave...
第二天 没了
And it was gone the next morning.
我知道你们觉得我很傻
I know you kids think it's silly.
我们不觉得那样很傻  外婆
We don't think it's silly, Waipo.
我们只知道外公希望你向前看
We just know Waigong would've wanted you to move on
享受你的生活
and enjoy your life.
“向前看”是美国人的想法
"Moving on" is an American idea.
你就是美国人,妈妈!不要忘记了
You're American, Mom! Don't forget.
肖恩
Shaun,
我女儿这周有应聘新工作吗?
did my daughter apply to any new jobs this week?
她真的很喜欢她的工作
She really likes her job.
我俩都喜欢
We both do.
嗯哼
Mm hmm.
外公从湖南搬来这
Waigong didn't move here from Hunan
不是让你靠停车谋生的
so you could park cars for a living.
说到这一点
Well, on that note,
我想我们要赶不上公车了
I think we're gonna miss our bus.
很抱歉 我这不能让人接受的工作
I'm sorry for my unacceptable job.
以及昨晚晚归
And for staying out late last night,
只是为了享受我的生活
trying to enjoy my life.
但总有一天 我会让你们感到骄傲的 我保证
But one day, I'll make you proud, I promise.
我为你感到骄傲 姐姐
I'm proud of you, sis.
停车超级难
Parking cars is super hard.
谢谢,兄弟
Thanks, bro.
也许有一天你会通过驾照考试
Maybe one day you'll pass your driver's test,
像我一样实现梦想
live the dream like me.
来吧 肖恩 我们走
Come on, Shaun, let's go.
走了 外婆
你们俩什么时候结婚?
When are you two going to get married?
外婆 我们只是朋友
Waipo, we're just friends.
噢  你走,走,走
All right. Go, go, go.
快看那个女孩
Look. Look at that. Look at that girl.
她在公车上写研究论文
She's writing a research paper on a bus.
所以呢?
So?
那就是我妈想要
That is exactly the daughter
生的那种女儿
my mom wishes came out of her vagina.
我为她感到难过
I'm sorry about her.
最近怎么样？
How's it goin'?
项链给我
Give me the pendant,
就没有人会受伤
and no one gets hurt.
你认识这家伙吗?
Do you know this guy?
我不知道你在说什么 兄弟
I don't know what you're talking about, dude.
嘿! 放开我!
Hey! Get off of me!   Whoa.
你有病吧 混蛋?
What is wrong with you, asshole?
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
那就把项链交出来!
Then give us the pendant!
你抓错人了!
You have the wrong guy!
他看起来像是会打架的人吗？
Does he look like he can fight?
放了他吧 兄弟!
Come on, bro!
你没事吧?
You okay?
嘿 你们好吗? 你们的克莱夫
Yo, what up, y'all? It's your boy Klev,
在公交车上为你们直播
comin' at you live on the bus.
实际上 我小时候
I actually did take
学过一点武术
a little bit of martial arts as a youth,
所以我要试着给这场搏斗打分
so I'm gonna try and grade this fight as we're goin'.
天呐
Holy shit.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你能行的 兄弟!
You got this, bro!
我的错
My bad.
不可以！
No, no, no!
不好意思
Sorry.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell's going on?
你真想现在谈这个吗?
You really wanna talk about this now?
巴士司机倒下了
Bus driver is down.
我才不会去管的
I'm not gonna handle this.
每次我试着开公交车的时候 都会被人吼
Every time I've tried to drive a bus, I get yelled at.
让开 你这个怪人
Go, you freak!
请把门打开!
Open the door, please!
后节车厢可以不要了
The back is about to go.
听我信号 等等往右急转弯
On my signal, make a hard right.
什么信号?
What signal?
大家都到前面去!
Everybody to the front now!
走吧!走,走,走
Go! Go, go, go.
发生什么事了！
What's up, y'all? What's up, y'all? What's up, y'all?
你和你妹妹罪有应得
You and your sister deserve what's coming.
站稳了 大伙!
Hold on, everybody!
哦 我的天
Oh, God.
哦,我的上帝!
Oh, my God!
不好意思哈
Sorry. Heh.
我们合作得很棒
We make a good team.
肖恩 嘿
Shaun. Hey.
你得告诉我到底发生了什么
You need to tell me what the hell's going on.
你在干什么?你要去哪里?
What are you doing? Where are you going?
澳门  澳门?
Macau.   Macau?
那些人接下来会去找我妹妹
Those guys are going after my sister next,
我得先找到她
and I have to get to her first.
你还有个妹妹?
You have a sister?
我知道这很让人困惑
Look, I know this is confusing.
等我回来再跟你解释 我保证
I'll explain it when I get back, I promise.
不,不
No, no.
绝对不可以 老兄
Hell no, dude.
你这是在胡闹呢？!
This is bullshit!
我陪了你半辈子
I have been by your side for half your life.
我知道有些事你一直不想谈
I get there are things you never wanted to talk about,
我也不想逼你谈
and I never wanted to push.
但是我们刚才遇到了一个手持大砍刀的人
But a guy with a freaking machete for an arm
把巴士切成了两半 肖恩!
just chopped our bus in half, Shaun!
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
我妹妹几个月前给我寄了这个
My sister sent me this a few months ago.
我想这是她住的地址
I think it's the address of where she's staying.
那些人是我爸爸派来的
Those guys back there were sent by my dad.
什么?
What?
如果他们伤害她…
If they hurt her...
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
很好
Fine.
你可以在飞机上解释
You can explain on the plane.
什么?不 凯蒂 你不能…
What? No, Katy, you can't just...
你可以在飞机上解释 肖恩!
You can explain on the plane, Shaun!
我妈妈死后…
After my mom died...
我爸爸开始训练我
my dad started my training.
日出到日落
From sunup to sundown,
我学过各种杀人的方法
I was taught every possible way to kill a man.
当我14岁的时候
By the time I was 14,
我几乎都不记得
I could barely remember
她死前的生活是什么样的了
what life was like before she died.
也正是14岁那年
That's how old I was
他派我去执行第一个任务
when he sent me on my first assignment.
我愿意为他做任何事
I was willing to do anything he wanted.
如果他让我毁掉这个世界
If he asked me to burn the world down,
我会问他…
I would've asked him...
牛肉还是素食
Beef or vegetarian?
我们没有鸡肉了
We're all out of the chicken,
所以你们是要牛肉还是素食呢？
so I can only offer you beef or vegetarian?
嗯…
Um...
素食很好  嗯 我也一样
Vegetarian would be great.   Yeah, same.
好的  谢谢
Okay.   Thank you.
所以…
So...
我们也没有素食了
Oh, we're out of the vegetarian too.
现在只有牛肉了
Now we only have beef.
牛肉 因为你们也只剩下牛肉了 对吧?
Beef. 'Cause that's all you have, right?
好的 你点的是牛肉  是的
Okay, you'll have the beef.   Yes.
那他...    牛肉
And...   Beef.
他也点牛肉  两份牛肉
And the beef.   Two beefs.
那你做了吗?
Did you go through with it?
我知道我不能回到他身边 所以我就…
I knew that I couldn't go back to him, so I just...
跑开了
ran.
我知道这对你来说很难接受
I know this is a lot to dump on you.
你妈妈的事我很遗憾
I'm sorry about your mom.
我还要提一下的是
I should also probably mention
严格来说我的名字不叫肖恩
that my name's not technically Shaun.
什么?
What?
那是什么?
What is it?
尚气
It's Shang Chi.
肖恩 气
Shaun Chi.
不 是尚气
No. Shang Chi.
肖恩 气
Shaun Chi.
尚
Shang.
肖恩  尚
Shaun.   Shang.
山
Shan.
S H A N G 尚
S H A N G. Shang.
尚吗?
Shang?
是的
Yeah.
你把名字从尚改成肖恩了?
You changed your name from Shang to Shaun?
是的,我不
Yeah, I don't... Yeah.
难怪你的父亲能找到你
I wonder how your father found you.
好吧 那时我才15岁 好吧?
Okay, I was 15 years old. All right?
你的改名逻辑是什么?
What is your name change logic?
你准备要躲起来了
You're going into hiding.
然后你的名字叫迈克尔
Okay.   And your name is Michael,
结果你就把它改成迈沙尔
you go on and change it to Mishael.
事实并非如此
That's not what happened.
就像 “嗨 我叫吉娜
It's like, "Hi, my name's Gina.
“我要躲起来了 我的新名字是G挨娜 ”
"I'm gonna go into hiding. My new name's Gina."
听不到你说的话了 抱歉
Can't hear you. I'm sorry.
哦 你能听到我说话的
Yeah, okay. Oh, yeah, you can hear me.
签字
Sign here to get in.
我在找我的妹妹 徐霞玲
I'm looking for my sister, Xu Xialing.
你听说过她吗?
Have you heard of her?
这里是她给我的地址
This is the address she gave me.
好吧
Okay.
看起来是个不错的人
Seems like a nice fella.
这电梯绝对符合标准
And this elevator is definitely up to code.
绝对不可能掉下到
There's absolutely no chance of it just falling off
大楼的另一侧…
the side of the building...
巴士男孩!
Bus Boy!
嗯…
Uh...
哇靠 你三天就两百万流量
Two million views in three days, bro!
厉害啊,兄弟
Damn, dude.
哦,天哪
Oh, no.
司机也来了
And you're the driver!
你的车技实在是太帅了
哦 我的中文糟透了
Oh, my Chinese sucks.
没事
Oh, all good.
我会说A B C  哦,太棒了
I speak A B C.   Oh, great.
我是乔恩·乔恩  乔恩·乔恩
I'm Jon Jon.   Jon Jon.
欢迎来到金匕首俱乐部
Welcome to the Golden Daggers Club.
好了 让我们为战斗做好准备
Okay, let's get you ready to fight.
等一下 什么?
Wait. What?
我们是一个多平台的全球公司
We're a multi platform global operation.
每一场战斗都在暗网上直播
Every fight livestreamed on the dark web.
我们说话的同时 成千上万的观众在下注
Thousands of viewers placing bets as we speak.
这会把你的名声提升到一个全新的高度
This is gonna take your brand to a whole new level.
我想一定是搞错了
Think there's been some sort of confusion.
我喜欢你的尖头脸
I like your spike face.
谢谢!
Thanks!
通常情况下 你得拼尽全力才能到中心圈
Usually, you gotta fight your way to centre ring,
但是像你这样的明星呢?
but a viral star like you?
直接就排在前面了 宝贝
Front of line, baby.
我不是来和任何人打架的 好吧?
I'm not here to fight anybody. Okay?
我在找我的妹妹 徐霞玲
I'm looking for my sister, Xu Xialing.
从没听说过她
Never heard of her.
我们刚在最后一刻失去了一名战士
We just lost a fighter at the last minute,
所以下一场 你上
so you get the next slot.
打得好,海伦
Nice one, Helen.
他会穿着这个打架吗?
Is he gonna be fighting in one of these?
哦 不 不 不 这些都是低级别的打斗
Oh, no, no, no. These are like low level fights.
你的是要在上面战斗
You're gonna be fighting up there.
很痛啊,埃米尔
That hurt, Emil.
你想试试那是什么感觉吗？
You want me to show you how it feels?
王！
Wong! Wong! Wong!
冲啊 王！
Go, Wong!
我总是赌亚洲人赢
I always bet on Asian.
哦,我的上帝
Oh, my God.
听着 我不会上去的 好吗?
Yeah, look, I'm not going up there, okay?
我只是想… 哇 哇 哇
I'm just trying to...   Whoa, whoa, whoa.
现在打退堂鼓已经太晚了
It's too late to back out now.
你已经承诺过了 兄弟  什么?
You already committed, bro.   What?
你签了合同 记得吗?
You signed the contract, remember?
你的名字在花名册上
Your name's on the roster.
赌注越来越多
The bets are piling in.
真的吗?我们有多少分成?  那可多了
Really? What's our cut?   Oh, it's huge.
那不重要
It doesn't matter.
很重要
It matters.
老兄 我看到你和五个杀手搏斗
Dude, I saw you fight five assassins
还有一个手上拿着利刃的罗马尼亚巨人
and a giant Romanian with a razor for an arm
在行驶的公共汽车上
on a moving bus.
这里只是一个人
This is just one guy.
快上吧 这样我们都可以得到报酬
Just do it. Then we all get paid,
然后我会帮你找到你要找的人
and then I'll help you find whoever you're looking for.
快上吧 你可以的
Come on. You got this.
你能行的  别紧张
You got this.   Don't be nervous.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
应该的
Yeah.   Yeah.
下巴怎么样?
How's the jaw?
能不能像我们练习的那样
Maybe you'll start controlling those punches
出拳？
like we practised?
太爱那家伙了
Love that guy.
把你的衬衫脱了
Now take your shirt off.
女士们,先生们,
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们期待已久的战斗
the fight we've all been waiting for.
从美国旧金山远道而来
The incredible viral sensation,
名声爆红的
all the way from San Francisco, USA,
巴士男孩!
it's Bus Boy!
你的衬衫怎么了?
What happened to your shirt?
而他今晚的对手
And his opponent for tonight,
澳门可怕的杀手……
it's Macau's own fearsome killer...
徐霞玲！
Xu Xialing!
妹妹
Sister.
等等,等等!
Wait, wait!
你怎么了？
What are you doing?
我知道你在生我的气
I know you're upset.
但是我有急事得跟你..
But can you hear me out?
没有时间打了
We don't have time for this.
哦 那一定很疼
Ooh, that's gotta hurt.
你能不能不打我了?
Can you please stop hitting me?
住手 我是来帮你的
Stop it! I'm trying to help you!
爸要来找你了
Dad's coming for you.
我不会再跟你打的
I'm not fighting you.
你不应该回来
You shouldn't have come back.
有的时候我在练功…
Sometimes when I'm doing my forms...
我闭上我的眼睛
I close my eyes,
就可以感觉她就在我身后
and it's like I can feel her.
你有这个感觉吗?
Do you ever feel like that?
没有
No.
我知道你要去那里做什么
I know what you're going there to do.
我不知道他跟你说了什么 但是妈妈…
I don't know what he's telling you, but Mom...
妈妈已经死了
Mom's dead.
不要把我扔在这
Please don't leave me here.
我三天以后就回来
I'll be back in three days.
徐霞玲 你太棒了!
Xu Xialing, you're amazing!
我们爱你 徐霞玲!哇!
We love you, Xu Xialing! Whoo!
这地方归你管？
You run this place?
这地方归我
I own it.
你从哪儿弄来那么多钱?
Where'd you get all that money?
你赌我输了吗?
Did you bet against me?
没有啊
No.
嗨,霞玲 我是凯蒂
Hi, Xialing. I'm Katy.
你真是太牛了
You're, like, such a badass.
你做的每件事都很酷
Everything that you do is, like, so cool.
那真的很酷
That was really cool.
我喜欢你的裤子
I like your pants.
谢谢你！谢谢
Thank you. Thanks. Yeah.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
十环帮在旧金山埋伏了我们
The Ten Rings ambushed us in San Francisco.
我看了视频
I saw the video.
他们拿走了我的项链
They took my pendant.
他们下一个就会来抢你的
They're gonna come for yours next.
我不知道他要他们做什么
I don't know what he wants with them,
但我们都知道不会是好事
but we both know it can't be good.
你知道他离开时对我说了什么吗?
You know what he said to me when he left?
“我三天后回来 ”
"I'll be back in three days."
三天后
And after three days,
我去了妈妈的神龛 等待着
I went to our mom's shrine and waited.
三天变成了一周
Three days turned into a week,
一周变成了一个月
a week turned to a month,
一个月变成了六年
and a month turned to six years.
我花了很长时间才意识到
That's how long it took me to realise
我不再需要他了
I didn't need him any more.
这地方是我自己建的
I built this place on my own.
我那时不需要你 现在也不需要你
I didn't need you then, and I don't need you now.
那你为什么要寄明信片给我?
Then why would you send me the postcard?
什么明信片?
What postcard?
我没把这个发给你
I didn't send you this.
有后门吗?
Is there a back exit?
肖恩
Shaun.
嘿 嘿!嘿,把门打开
Hey. Hey! Hey, open up!
她走了,伙计
She's gone, dude.
我们该怎么办?
What do we do?
嗯…
Uh...
来吧!
Come on!
哦, 我才不要 滚吧! 我不会这么做的
Oh, hell no. Screw you! I'm not doing this.
如果我们能到电梯
If we make it to the elevator,
我们可以去下一层
we can hop in on the next floor.
凯蒂 我们别无选择了 我们得走了
Katy, we're out of options. We have to go now.
一二三
One, two, three.
哇
Whoa.
直接去那部电梯
Just head straight for that elevator.
你可以的
You got this.
我会给你争取一些时间 你先走
I'll buy you some time. Just keep going.
On a dark desert highway
Eagles Hotel California
Cool wind in my hair
肖恩!
Shaun!
肖恩!肖恩!
Shaun! Shaun!
哦,我的天 !哦!
Oh, my God! Ohhh!
我来了!
I'm coming!
肖恩!
Shaun!
坚持下去
Hang on.
抓住你了
Gotcha.
肖恩!
Shaun!
凯蒂!
Katy!
我把我丢在这 说走就走啊!
You left us for dead!
现在你知道什么滋味了
Now you know how it feels.
他要这个项链干什么…
What does he want with the pendant...
美国让你变得软弱了吗?
Did America make you soft?
他拿了项链！
He has the pendant!
我告诉我的手下
I told my men
就算他们想杀你 也杀不了你
they wouldn't be able to kill you if they tried.
很高兴我是对的
Glad I was right.
我太想你了
I've missed you, my son.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我儿子回家了
My son is home.
带姑娘们去她们的房间
Take the girls to their room.
这周我看到了一些非常可怕的东西
I've seen some really scary stuff this week,
但你爸爸就像在另一个层面
but your dad's on, like, a whole 'nother level.
他会杀了我们吗?
Is he gonna kill us?
只需要点头 不要说话 他会忘记你的存在的
Just nod. Don't talk. He'll forget you're there.
我就是这样活下来的
That's how I survived.
他总是那样对你吗?
He always treat you like that?
在我妈妈去世之后
Only after my mom died.
他说他不敢看我 因为我让他想起了她
He said he couldn't look at me because I reminded him of her.
他不允许我和男孩们一起训练
I wasn't allowed to train with the boys.
我们学着他们所训练的一切
But I watched everything they did
并教会自己做得更好
and taught myself to do it better.
你什么时候离开的?
When did you leave?
我16岁就离家出走了
I ran away when I was 16.
当我知道我哥哥不会回来的时候
As soon as I knew my brother wasn't coming back.
你在澳门开了一个地下拳馆
You started an underground fight ring in Macau
在你16岁的时候?
when you were 16 years old?
如果我爸不让我进入他的帝国
If my dad won't let me into his empire,
我要自己建一个
I'm gonna build my own.
那当然
Hell yeah.
尚气
Shang Chi.
可以了
That's enough.
你一直在练习英语吗?
Have you been practicing your English?
是的
Yes.
你必须加强你身心合一的能力
You have to strengthen your mind along with your body.
如果你想让它们有一天属于你
If you want them to be yours one day,
你得向我证明你有足够能力肩负起它们
you have to show me you're strong enough to carry them.
你怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
我总是知道我孩子在哪里
I always know where my children are.
我给了你十年自己生活
I gave you 10 years to live your life,
看看你现在都什么样了?
and where did it get you?
现在是你回到我身边的时候了
Now it's time for you to take your place by my side.
那是不可能的
That's not gonna happen.
美国女孩
American girl.
她的名字叫凯蒂
Her name is Katy.
你的中文名字是什么?
What is your Chinese name?
瑞文
Ruiwen.
名字是神圣的 瑞文
Names are sacred, Ruiwen.
它们不仅与我们自己有联系
They connect us not only to ourselves,
和先辈也有关联
but to everyone who came before.
一个有趣的故事
A funny story.
几年前 有个美国的恐怖分子
Some years ago, a terrorist from America
想要有个恶魔去
needed a boogeyman
让你们的国家屈服
to bring your country to its knees.
所以他挪用了十环
So, he appropriated The Ten Rings.
我的十环
My Ten Rings.
但他不知道我的真名
But because he didn't know my actual name,
所以他取了个新的名字
he invented a new one.
你知道他取的啥吗?
Do you know the name he chose?
满大人
The Mandarin.
他给傀儡起了一道鸡肉菜的名字
He gave his figurehead the name of a chicken dish.
然后就起作用了
And it worked.
美国吓坏了
America was terrified.
就因为一个橘子
Of an orange.
实际上
The truth is,
我这辈子有过很多名字
I've had many names throughout my life.
勇士之王 可汗大师
The Warrior King, Master Khan,
地球上最危险的人
the most dangerous man on Earth.
多年来 我一直以为那是我命中注定的
For years, I thought that was all I was meant to be.
但当我见到他们的母亲时
But when I met their mother,
一切都改变了
everything changed.
她让我看到了一直藏在我内心深处的那个人
She showed me a part of myself I didn't know was there.
就好像我第一次看到这个世界一样
It was like I was seeing the world for the first time.
为了我们能在一起 她放弃了一切
She gave up everything so we could be together.
我也一样
And so did I.
你知道谁在里面吗?
You know who's in there?
说 “你好 小妹妹!”
Say, "Hello, little sister!"
这么多年过去了
After all those years,
我终于找到了
I finally found something
能让我为之变老的东西
worth growing old for.
我的真名是文武
My real name is Wenwu.
只有她这么叫我
She was the only one who called me that.
她死的时候…
And when she died...
我迷失了很多年
I was lost for many years.
但我不再迷茫了
But I'm not lost any more.
当你们这些孩子逃跑时
When you children ran away,
我太想和你母亲交流了
I was so desperate to connect with your mother,
我重新投入到她的村庄的研究中
I threw myself back into the studies of her village.
传奇的塔罗
The legendary Ta Lo.
我找不到
I wasn't able
通往村庄入口的秘密通道
to find the secret path to the village entrance,
但我发现了他们隐藏的东西
but I did find what they are hiding.
他们的山深处有一扇门
There's a gate deep in their mountains.
你妈妈在那儿等我们
Your mother is waiting for us there.
我知道这难以置信
I know this is a lot.
要不是她亲口告诉我 我可能也不相信
I might not have believed it if she didn't tell me herself.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我就坐在这个座位上
I was sitting right here in this seat,
研究我的东西
deep in my research...
听到她对我说
and she spoke to me.
就好像她就站在这个房间里
It was like she was standing in this room.
我能感觉到她在我脸颊上的呼吸
I could feel her breath on my cheek
还有她的手放在我背上
and her hand on my back.
她说她需要我的帮助
She told me she needs my help.
要干什么?
To do what?
把她从她的族人手中救出来
To save her from her people.
在我们相爱之后
After we fell in love,
你妈妈想让我们住在塔罗
your mother wanted us to live in Ta Lo.
她请求长老们的许可
She asked permission from the elders,
他们拒绝了
and they refused.
他们说我不配
They said I wasn't worthy.
她本还可以和我们在一起
She would still be with us.
我们会一起住在那里
We would all be living there together.
都是塔罗族人害的
Ta Lo did this to us.
他们把她锁在门后惩罚她
They locked her behind that gate to punish her.
你们还不明白吗？
Don't you see?
她给我们留下了线索
She's leaving clues for us.
她想让我们找到她
She wants us to find her
把她带回家 这样我们就能再次成为一家人
and bring her home, so we can be a family again.
爸爸,妈妈已经走了
Dad, Mom's gone.
她没有在一个门后和你讲话
She's not talking to you from behind a gate,
她也不会给我们留下什么线索了
and she's not leaving any clues for us.
那这些是什么？
Then what are these?
通往大罗的通道由一个移动的迷宫守卫着
The passage to Ta Lo is guarded by a moving maze.
但有一条可以直接穿过竹林的路
But there's a direct path through the forest
一年只开一次
that only opens once a year
在清明节
on Qingming Jie.
要想通过 你需要知道路线
To get through, you need to know the route
以及它打开的确切时间
and the exact time it opens.
现在我都知道了
Now I know both.
三天以后
Three days from now,
我们要把我妻子从禁锢中救出来
we will rescue my wife from her prison
把她带回家
and bring her home.
这就是你来这里的原因
This is why you're here.
帮我把她带回来
To help me bring her back to us.
如果他们不让你开门呢?
And what happens if they don't let you open the gate?
那我们就把村子烧成灰烬
We'll burn the village to the ground.
什么?
What?
你不能就这么闯进我妈的村子
You can't just march into our mom's village
就因为这荒谬的理由
with this bullshit.
我是说 你自己说的话你信吗...
I mean, do you have any idea how insane...
嘿!
Hey!
你要带我去哪里?
Where are you taking me?
你还要装多久？
When will you stop pretending?
把他们关起来
Lock them up.
没关系 亲爱的
It's okay, my dear.
咱们一家人很快就能在一起了
We're all going to be together soon.
所以我现在很困惑
So, um, pretty confused right now,
因为 一开始我觉得你爸那幻觉应该
because, uh, initially I thought your dad should
要去看心理医生的
definitely see a therapist for his delusions,
但后来那条龙吐了一张魔法水图
but then that dragon vomited a magical water map,
现在我不知道什么是真实的了
and now I have no idea what's real.
他说的你妈妈的村子是真的吗?
Is what he said about your mom's village true?
她常给我们讲塔罗的故事
She used to tell us stories about Ta Lo
当我们还是孩子的时候
when we were kids.
一个充满神奇生物 在另一个维度的村庄
A village in another dimension full of magical creatures.
我以为那只是个童话故事
I thought it was just a fairy tale.
如果爸爸是对的呢?
What if Dad's right?
妈妈被自己人
About Mom being locked behind a gate
锁在门后的事?
by her own people?
疯狂的事情往往最后都是真的
Crazier things have turned out to be true.
听着 我不知道到底是怎么回事
Look, I don't know what the hell is going on,
但如果我们不能在他之前去到塔罗
but if we don't find a way to get to Ta Lo before him,
他会毁掉我们家所剩下的一切
he's gonna destroy everything that's left of our family.
这个家庭很久以前就被毁了
This family was destroyed a long time ago.
那是什么鬼东西?
The hell was that?
哦
Oh.
你要去听那声音吗?
You're going toward that noise?
“用你的敲门声把邓肯吵醒
"Wake Duncan with thy knocking.
“哦 我想我可以
"Oh, I would'st though could'st.
“我做的事最好不要……”
"My deed 'twere best not..."
哦,亲爱的 你们好
Oh, hello, loves.
现在是哪一年?
What year is it?
你是谁?
Who are you?
特雷弗?Slattery吗?
Trevor? Slattery?
那个来自利物浦的演员?
The actor from Liverpool?
等一下
Wait.
你们是管理者的孩子吗?
Are you the governor's kids?
我为你的返宴
I've been preparing a monologue
准备了一段独白
for your homecoming dinner.
哦 她要去哪里?
Oh. Where's she going?
你为什么在这下面?
Why are you down here?
一段时间以前
Well, some time ago,
他们让我扮演恐怖分子的角色
I was offered the role of a terrorist.
我知道 肤浅 陈腐 我完全同意
I know, facile, trite, I couldn't agree more.
但时局艰难 你懂我的意思吗?
But times were lean, you know what I mean?
不管怎样 制片人告诉我他为BBC工作
Anyway, the producer told me he worked for the BBC.
但是,谁能想到..
But, ironic twist,
事实上 他是个恐怖分子
it turns out he, in fact, was a terrorist,
我根本不知道扮演的是什么角色
and I wasn't playing a character at all,
但我现在明白了 扮演的是你父亲
but what I now recognise to be
那不讨人喜欢的角色
a rather unflattering portrait of your father.
我们都得到应有的惩罚
We all got our just deserts.
制片人被钢铁侠炸飞了
The producer got blown up by Iron Man,
我在联邦监狱服刑
and I served time in federal prison,
这对我来说是最好的事情
which turned out to be the best thing for me.
我戒了毒 重拾了激情
I got clean, I rediscovered my passion.
然后我爸爸把你救出来了? 没错
Then my dad broke you out?   Exactly.
只是为了把你杀了  没错
To kill you.   Exactly.
但正当他手下把我
But just as his men
绑起来准备处决的时候
were tying me up for my execution,
我开始表演我的麦克白
I launched into a performance of my Macbeth.
“敲门声是从哪儿来的?”随着邓肯
"Whence is that knocking? Wake Duncan
“你的敲门 我想我能……”
"with thy knocking. I would'st though could'st..."
他们怎么也看不够
They couldn't get enough of it.
从那以后 我每周都为小伙子们表演
I've been doing weekly gigs for the lads ever since.
所以你就像他的小丑?
So you're like his jester?
我可以给你们快速展示一下 如果你们想看的话
I can give you a quick preview if you like.
谢谢 特雷弗 我想我们就算了
Uh, thank you, Trevor. I think we're okay.
现在 我们真的需要找到一个方法…
Right now, we really just need to find a way to...
这到底是怎么回事?
What the hell?
什么……哦!
What the... Oh!
哇! 那是什么?
Whoa!   What is that?
什么是什么?
What's what?
那是什么? !那!那!
That! What is that?   That! That! That!
你能看到莫里斯吗?
You can see Morris?
莫里斯?
Morris?
哦,莫里斯!
Oh, Morris!
他们能看见你!你是真的!
They can see you! You're real!
我一直以为是我产生了幻觉
All this time I thought I was hallucinating him.
这真是太棒了
Oh, this is such fab news.
他的脸在哪里?
Where's his face?
他对此有点敏感
He's a bit sensitive about that.
哦 真的吗?
Oh. Really?
莫里斯说他知道你是谁
Morris says he knows who you are.
…它和你说话?
It talks... It talks to you?
如果他不跟我说话
If he didn't talk to me,
我早就疯了
I'd have gone mad yonks ago.
他怎么会认识我?
How would he know me?
他说他是和你妈妈一起长大的 在塔罗
He says he grew up with your mum. In Ta Lo.
很显然 你父亲是在魔法竹林里找到他的
Apparently, your father picked him up in some magic forest
在一次寻找入口的探险中
on one of his expeditions to find the entrance.
他想让你带他回家
He wants you to take him home.
相信我 兄弟 如果我知道该怎么做 我会的
Believe me, buddy, I would if I knew how.
据我爸爸说
According to my dad,
那条路一年只开放一次
the path there only opens once a year.
哦
Oh.
莫里斯说他可以马上带你过去
Morris says he can guide you there right now.
你可以穿过迷宫
You can get through the maze
而不是等它自己开启
without waiting for the path to open.
但是 这是个巨大的转折 “但是”
But, and it's a big "but,"
这是非常危险的
it's very dangerous.
有多危险?
How dangerous?
没人能活着出来
No one's ever made it out alive.
但莫里斯有90%的信心
But Morris is 90% confident
他能引导我们安全通过
he can guide us through safely.
哦
Oh.
19%
19%.
听着 我做过比这更蠢的事
Look, I've done dumber things with worse odds.
但即使那只鸡猪是对的……
But even if that chicken pig is right...
我们还被锁在你的…
...we're still locked in your...
唷!
Whew!
你是怎么……
How did you...
爸爸在整个院子下面有个隧道系统
Dad has a tunnel system under the whole compound.
我上次就是这样逃出来的
That's how I escaped last time.
哦
Oh.
这能直接把我们带到车库
This will take us straight to the garage.
哦,我的上帝
Oh, my God.
我有点喜欢这家伙
I kinda like this guy.
顺着斜坡走 穿过前门
Just head up that ramp and through the front gate.
应该可以直接出去
Should be a straight shot.
我们大概还有30秒…
Figure we got about 30 seconds until he...
你介意吗?
Do you mind?
我在后面会生病 晕车的
I get sick in the back. Carsick.
那可是我的车!
That's my car!
该死的
God damn it.
坐稳了
Hold on.
还有别的出口吗?
Is there another exit?
车库的另一头
The other end of the garage.
但我们需要指纹才能打开它
But we need a fingerprint to open it.
小心袭击！
Incoming!
妈的！
Shit!
后面发生了什么?
What's happening back there?
我在尽力了
Doing my best.
扫描手印 通过大门
Scan hand print for gate access.
快点! 我在努力了！
Hurry up!   I'm trying!
扫描手印 通过大门
Scan hand print for gate access.
肖恩!
Shaun!
获得批准
Access approved.
等我把她带回家 他们就会回来
They will come back once I bring her home.
让人们备战
Prepare the men for war.
收到,先生
Yes, sir.
我第一次目睹了纯粹的艺术
The first time I witnessed pure artistry.
1968 人猿星球
1968. Planet of the Apes.
我在电影院里坐在我妈旁边
I was sitting in the cinema next to my mum,
看着佳作
watching mastery
就在我眼前展开
unfold before my very eyes.
看完电影后 我问她
After the film, I asked her,
“他们是怎么让那些猴子做那些事情的?”
"How did they get those monkeys to do those things?"
她拍拍我的头说
And she patted me on the head and she said,
“这不是真的 宝贝 这只是表演 ”
"It's not real, pet. It's just acting."
那时我才知道
That's when I knew.
如果他们能教那些猴子
If they can teach those monkeys
表现得如此出色
to act that brilliantly,
想象一下我能给这个世界带来什么
just imagine what I could bring to the world.
所以你成了一名演员
So you became an actor
因为你认为猴子实际上…
because you thought the monkeys were actually...
会骑马吗? 是的 我就是这么认为的
Riding horses? I did. Yes.
事实上,
When, in fact,
他们只是表现得像在骑马一样
they were simply acting as if they were riding horses.
说实话 我还是不明白
I still can't get my head round it, to be honest.
干得好 伙计
Good for you, dude.
你找到了你的激情并去追求它
You found your passion and went for it,
而且最终用它
and eventually used it
削弱美国政府 但管他呢
to cripple the US government, but whatever.
是的 不,是的,谢谢
Yeah. No, yeah, thanks.
这真的很酷
Um, this is really cool and all,
但我们还要在这坐多久?
but how long do we have to sit here?
莫里斯说得很清楚
Morris is very clear.
这一切都取决于时机
The way through is all about timing.
好吧 但我们要谈多久?
Okay, but how long are we talking?
几个小时?还是几天?
Like, hours? Days?
朋友 我只是这个无限智慧生物
Friends, I am but a transitory vessel
传话人
for the infinite wisdom of a creature
它远比我们所能真正理解的超前
far more advanced than we'll ever truly understand.
他所看到的 感觉到的
What he sees, what he feels
在这浩瀚无穷的宇宙
of this vast, unknown universe
不是我们这简单的大脑所能…
is beyond anything our simple brains can...
哦 你可以走了
Oh. You can go.
什么?
What?
走了 可以走了 他说:“快走”
Go. You can go. He says "go."
你得加快速度
You should speed up.
什么?为什么?
What? Why?
凯蒂 快 快 快!
Katy, go, go, go!
莫里斯说,
Morris says,
“数到三 向右急转弯 ” 什么?
"Hard right on three."   What?
二
Two...
哪里急转弯？
Hard right where?
就现在
Now.
然后向左
And left.
我们只需要呆在袋子里
It's all about staying in the pocket.
什么袋子? 我们现在就在里面
What pocket?   We're in it now.
如果我们不在里面怎么办?
What happens if we don't stay in the pocket?
竹林在吃我们
The forest eats us.
吃我们吗?这是什么意思?
Eats us? What does that mean?
他说它会吃了我们 向左
He says it eats us. Go left.
小心! 呆在口袋里
Watch your back!   Stay in the pocket.
有多近?  5米
How close is it?   Five metres.
呆在口袋里  那是多少英尺?
Stay in the pocket.   What is that in feet?
非常接近
Really fricking close.
呆在口袋里
Stay in the pocket.
你能别再说"呆在口袋里"了吗?
Will you just stop saying, "Stay in the pocket"?
最后一个右转 然后一直走到尽头
One last right, then straight on to the end.
你最好快点
You might wanna hurry up.
你以为我在干什么?
What do you think I'm doing?
我们撑不过去了
We're not gonna make it.
我要回家了 妈妈
I'm coming home, Mummy.
莫里斯说:“大家干得好 ”
Morris says, "Great job, everyone."
现在我们要做的就是穿过那个瀑布
Now, all we have to do is go through that waterfall,
我们差不多要到了
and we're pretty much there.
天哪
Bloody hell.
我觉得那些鸟着火了
I think those birds are on fire.
真的吗?哦
Really? Oh.
莫里斯说这很正常
Morris says it's normal.
他们是他的老朋友
They're old mates of his.
那是匹奇怪的马
That's a weird horse.
它为什么看着我?
What's it looking at me for?
大家好!
Hi there!
我是徐尚气
I am Xu Shang Chi.
这是我的妹妹 徐霞玲
This is my sister, Xu Xialing.
我们是英莉的孩子
We're Ying Li's children.
这是我的朋友凯蒂
This is my friend, Katy.
上车 哪来的回哪去
Get in your car and go home!
您误会了 您听我们说
Please. You don't understand.
哇
Whoa.
光博
Guang Bo!
你们这是在干什么?
What are you doing?
放下你们的武器!
Put down your weapons!
尚气
Shang Chi.
霞玲
Xialing.
我是你们的小姨 楠姨
I'm your aunty Nan.
我终于见到你了
I've waited so long to meet you.
你像你妈妈
You look like your mother.
你好,我是凯蒂
Hi, I'm Katy.
欢迎来到塔罗 凯蒂
Welcome to Ta Lo, Katy.
噢,谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
看谁找到回家的路了!
Look who has found his way home!
我不是威胁
I'm not a threat.
只是一个艺人
Just an entertainer.
莫里斯可以为我担保
Morris can vouch for me.
我们没有多少时间了
We don't have much time.
我们的父亲要来了
Our father is coming.
我们的人民已经在这里生活了4000多年
Our people have been here for over 4,000 years,
为我们希望永远不会发生的事情做准备
preparing for something we hope will never happen.
我们是黑暗之门的守护者
We are the keepers of the Dark Gate,
发誓要保护你我的王国
sworn to protect this realm and yours
远离被锁在后面的恶魔
from the evil that's locked behind it.
我们的爸爸要来打开那扇门
Our dad is coming here to open that gate.
他认为你把我们的妈妈关在那里
He thinks you're holding our mom there.
他为什么会这么想?
Why would he think that?
她告诉他
She told him.
他说他听到她在寻求帮助
He says he can hear her asking for help.
他戴着十环吗?
Is he wearing the rings?
自从她死后 他就没摘下过
He hasn't taken them off since she died.
他们和这一切有什么关系?
What do they have to do with all this?
塔罗的疆域远远比我们小村庄的海岸
The realm of Ta Lo stretches far beyond
要大的多
the shores of our small village.
我们的城市比你们宇宙中的任何城市都要多
We have cities that surpass any in your universe,
具有丰富的文化和历史
rich with culture and history.
几千年前
Thousands of years ago,
我们的人民生活在和平与繁荣之中
all of our people lived in peace and prosperity,
直到黑暗居住者的攻击
until the attack of the Dweller in Darkness.
他带着他的军队来了
He came with his army,
吞噬他们路上的每一个灵魂
devouring every soul in their path,
每杀一一个人 他们就变得更强
and with each kill, they grew stronger.
在摧毁了我们最大的城市之后
After decimating our largest cities,
他们也要去你的宇宙做同样的事
they were headed to your universe to do the same.
塔罗的首领派了他们最强大的战士来这里
The leaders of Ta Lo sent their strongest warriors here
阻止他们到达你们世界的入口
to stop them from reaching the portal to your world.
但我们的祖先不是他们的对手
But our ancestors were no match for them.
直到伟大的保护者
Until The Great Protector
加入了战斗 扭转了局势
joined their fight and turned the tide.
他们把黑暗居住者和他的军队
Together, they pushed the Dweller and his army
关回黑暗之门了
into the Dark Gate
然后把它锁起来
and locked it behind them.
我们的人一直守着那扇门
Our people have guarded that gate ever since,
被伟大守护者的魔法赋予力量
empowered by the magic of The Great Protector
还有你妈妈给我们的礼物
and the gift that she gave us.
龙鳞
Dragon scales.
这是很好的盔甲
Makes very good armour.
你父亲不是第一个要来这里
Your father isn't the first to come here
打开黑暗之门的人
to open the Dark Gate.
几个世纪以来 许多人都尝试过 但都失败了
Many have tried and failed over the centuries,
他们都有一个共同点
and they all had one thing in common.
他们是被另一边的声音
They were lured here
引诱到这里来的
by the voice of something on the other side.
这个声音向他们承诺了他们最大的愿望
A voice that promised them their greatest desires.
所以你认为食魂者在和我们的父亲谈话?
So you think soul eaters are talking to our dad?
他们知道十环有能力让他们自由
They know The Ten Rings have the power to break them free.
哦
Oh.
给你
Here you go.
哦
Oh.
去射箭场
To the range.
什么?好吧
What? Okay.
看来我要去送龙箭了
Um, looks like I'm gonna go deliver some dragon arrows.
你要送龙箭吗?
Oh, you're gonna deliver some dragon arrows?
是的 让自己变得有用 你知道的
Yeah. Make myself useful, you know.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我们去看你妈妈吧
Let's go see your mother.
我就是喜欢你们知道自己想做什么
I just love how you guys know exactly what you wanna do,
然后你花了一辈子的时间变得非常擅长
and you spend your whole life getting really good at it.
我希望我能像你那样
I wish I was more like that.
好像每次我稍微擅长某件事
It's like every time I get moderately good at something,
我就退出了 去开始新的生活
I just quit and start something new.
但我知道自己的极限
But I just know my own limits,
我不会把时间浪费在追逐什么东西上
and I'm not gonna waste my time chasing something
这最终会让我失望的
that will ultimately be a disappointment for me.
那不是我
That's not me.
光博
Guang Bo.
让她试试
Let her shoot.
如果你心中没有靶子 就是我无的放矢
If you aim at nothing, you hit nothing.
你们是她的一切
You were everything to her.
她知道有一天你会找到来这里的路
She knew that one day you would find your way here
让我为你的到来准备东西
and asked me to prepare something for your arrival.
在失去像她这样的人之后
After losing someone like her,
在这个世界上很容易感到孤独
it's easy to feel alone in this world.
但你们不会
But you're not.
你们是这个家的孩子
You are children of this family,
我会欢迎你们回家
and I welcome you home.
这里不是你父亲家了
You're not in your father's house any more.
在塔罗 每个人都可以练武
In Ta Lo, we train as equals.
是时候从影子里走出来了 孩子
You've been in the shadows long enough, my child.
光博 你看到了吗?
Guang Bo, you saw that?
我还挺准的！!
That was tight!
我母亲是唯一能打败他的人
My mother was the only one who could beat him.
告诉我她是怎么做的
Show me how she did it.
不,不好意思
No, sorry.
不好意思 往右边站
Sorry. Offside, offside.
你妈妈知道她是谁
Your mother knew who she was.
你呢?
Do you?
你是所有前人的产物
You are a product of all who came before you.
你家族的遗产 无论好坏
The legacy of your family, the good and the bad,
这都是你的一部分
it is all a part of who you are.
不要再隐藏了,侄子
Stop hiding, nephew.
它只会更痛苦
It only prolongs the pain.
我们很快就能团聚了
We'll be together soon.
先生
Sir.
士兵们准备好了
The men are ready.
通道将在黎明时打开
The passage will open at dawn.
我去准备车
I'll prepare the vehicles.
以心行气
Lead with your breath.
以气运身
Look into your heart,
要先掌握阴阳的转换
the light and the dark.
你才能找到内心的平衡
To know yourself,
从而真正认识自己
you must face them both.
你丈夫想灭了我的门
Your husband tried to destroy us.
我们今天是来回礼的
The Iron Gang is here to repay that debt.
他已经不是以前那个人了
My husband is not the man he used to be.
那我不管
It doesn't matter.
你们之间的事情跟我的孩子们无关
Your business with him has nothing to do with my children.
放了他们可以
They can go,
但这个礼 必须得有人来接吧
but someone has to pay.
玲玲  尚气
Xialing. Shang Chi.
进屋去
Go inside.
我跟客人有话要说
I'm going to talk to our guests.
可你现在没有魔法了呀
But you don't have your powers.
尚气 别怕
Shang Chi, you have nothing to fear.
妈妈
Mama.
爸爸
Papa.
她说我是可以改变的
She told me I could change.
我也可以放下一切
That I could leave my past behind.
可是她错了
But she was wrong.
如果我当初没有把它们摘下来
If I hadn't taken them off,
那些混蛋根本就不敢动手
those men wouldn't have dared to do this.
我要让他们付出代价
And now they will pay for it.
你老板呢？
Where's your boss?
我不知道!
I don't know!
我真的不知道!
I swear I don't!
那好吧
Okay.
血债必须要血偿
A blood debt has to be paid by blood.
你愿意帮爸爸吗？
Will you help me?
我们找到了那个
We found the man
杀死你母亲的凶手
responsible for killing your mother.
你有权利为我们俩了结这件事
It is your right to finish this for both of us.
当你回来的时候
And when you return,
我们会把十环重建成原来的样子
we will rebuild The Ten Rings to what it once was.
我在到处找你
Been looking everywhere for ya.
你没事吧?
You okay?
我不是你想的那种人
I'm not who you think I am.
你已经为此道歉了 我们好…
You already apologised for that. We're good...
我说的不是这个
That's not what I'm talking about.
好吧
Okay.
那是什么？
What... What is it?
我爸派我去找杀我妈的凶手
When my dad sent me to find the man who killed my mom...
我告诉过你我做不到
I told you I couldn't go through with it.
我说谎了
I lied.
我以为我可以改名字
I thought that I could change my name,
开始新的生活 假装什么都没发生过
start a new life, pretend like it never happened.
但是…
But...
她会讨厌现在的我
She would hate the person I've become.
你爸爸训练你成为一名杀手
Your dad trained you to be an assassin
在你七岁的时候
when you were seven.
他在你14岁就派你去杀人了
He sent you on a hit at 14.
你知道这有多糟糕吧?
You realise how messed up that is, right?
我妈妈因为他而死
My mom is dead because of him.
现在他要来毁掉她的家
And now he's coming to destroy her home.
血债必须要血偿
A blood debt has to be paid by blood.
你在说什么?
What are you saying?
我要做他训练我做的事
I'm gonna do what he trained me to do.
我要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
他来了
He's here.
不行!
No!
你还没准备好
You're not ready.
她留下
She stays here.
你是来帮
Are you here to help the people
囚禁自己母亲的人吗?
holding your own mother captive?
她不在那后面
She isn't back there.
你被一个想要毁灭我们
You're being lied to
所有人的生物给骗了
by a creature who wants to destroy us all.
他们是这么告诉你的吗?
Is that what they told you?
我认得我妻子的声音
I know my wife's voice.
我和你一样想念我妹妹
I miss my sister as much as you do,
但这不是纪念她的方式
but this is not the way to honour her memory.
你把她从家门赶走
Did you honour her when you turned her away
是为了她吗？
from your gate?
你混帐 我们拒绝的人是你
You fool. We turned you away.
你过去造的孽 会毁了这个地方
The sins of your past would have destroyed this place.
小子 跟我讲话礼貌点
Be careful how you speak to me, young man.
我吃的盐比你吃的饭还多
I've lived ten of your lifetimes.
让我过去
Let me pass.
你想得美
We cannot do that.
把这毁了
Burn it down.
阻止他!
Stop him!
你就打算一个人阻止我吗?
Are you planning to stop me all by yourself?
我才不怕你
I'm not afraid of you.
你当然怕我
Yes, you are.
你一生都在恐惧中度过
You've spent your entire life afraid.
一直在逃避
Always running,
一直在躲藏
always hiding.
他们来抓她的时候你在场
You were there when they came for her,
而你什么都没做
and you did nothing.
你站在窗边看着她死去!
You stood at a window and watched her die!
她死了 我们需要你
She was gone and we needed you.
但你选择了那些该死的环而不是我们
But you chose those damn rings over us.
你把你儿子训练成杀手
You trained your son to be a killer.
这是你想要的吗?
Is this what you wanted?
就算你能让她复活
Even if you could bring her back,
你凭什么觉得她会想跟你扯上关系?
what makes you think she'd want anything to do with you?
来救我
Save me.
快来救我
Save me, my dear.
救我
Save me.
我们回家
I'm coming, my love.
他闯到大门了!
He breached the gate!
那些东西会害死我们所有人的
Those things are gonna kill us all
如果我们不合作的话
if we don't work together.
你以为我会信你的话吗?
You think I'm going to fall for that?
你们的武器对他们没用
Your weapons are useless against them.
我们才不需要你们的帮助
We don't need your help.
我们是强大的十环军队
We are the mighty Ten Rings,
以及任何一个…
and any...
我们……我们应该合作
We... We should work together.
放了他们
Release them.
放了他们!
Release them!
它们在做什么?
What are they doing?
汲取灵魂来喂养黑暗居住者
Stealing souls to feed the Dweller in Darkness.
如果它足够强大
If it grows strong enough,
它会冲破大门的
it will break right through the gate.
而那仅仅是个开始
That was just the beginning.
太危险了
It's too dangerous.
我必须帮助我的朋友
I have to help my friends.
活着回来
Don't die.
所有人马上到湖边集合!
Everyone to the water now!
到湖那去! 我们走吧!
To the lake! Let's go!
快点！!
Let's go!
嘿 你哥哥呢?
Hey, where's your brother?
我还以为你知道
I was hoping you knew.
救我
Save me.
齐天共战 视死如归
Aim at the sky, to win or die!
深吸一口气
Deep breath.
尚气 别怕
Shang Chi, you have nothing to fear.
你有神龙之心
You have the heart of our dragon.
你是妈妈的血脉 也是爸爸的
I will always be a part of you. And your dad will too.
你要把我们给你的一切化成自己的力量
Take everything we've given you and make it your own.
你是妈妈的骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
我们的家需要你
Our family needs you.
去吧
Go.
开弓
Draw.
放箭
Fire!
你必须阻止你父亲!
You have to stop your father!
她不在那里面 爸爸
She's not back there, Dad.
别挡我的路 小子
Get out of my way, boy.
我不
No.
冷静点 兄弟
Calm down, mate.
我还没死呢 我是演的
I'm not dead, it's just a performance.
快躺下跟我一起演戏
Now get down here and play along.
我必须救她
I have to save her.
她在召唤我
She's calling to me.
我倒希望是真的
I wish that were true.
爸爸,求你了
Dad, please.
你的家人需要你
Your family needs you.
放我出去!
Let me out!
妈的
Shit.
它朝村子去了!
It's headed for the village!
如果神龙的灵魂被吞掉了
If it gets our dragon's soul,
到时候什么也阻止不了他
it will be unstoppable!
对准它的喉咙!
Aim for the throat!
放手吧
You have to let me go.
放手！
Let go!
我不会再离开你了
I'm not leaving you again.
天呐
Holy shit.
去吧
Go.
今晚,
Tonight,
我们向那些献出生命的人致敬
we honour those who gave their lives
因为他们 我们得以看到明天
so we might see another day.
他们不仅仅是战士
They were more than warriors.
他们是我们的父母
They were our mothers and fathers,
我们的兄弟姐妹
our sisters and brothers.
虽然我们会永远铭记他们
And though we will always hold on to their memories,
但今晚我们放下他们与祖先一同安息
tonight we release them to rest with our ancestors.
爸 走好
Farewell, Dad.
妈妈 放心吧
Mum, we'll be okay.
一千年前
A thousand years ago,
一千年之后
and a thousand years from now,
我们将永远在一起
we will always be together.
我真的以为我们会死
I seriously thought we were going to die.
一天前我才刚学会
And I'd only learned how to shoot a bow,
射箭
like, a day earlier,
下一秒我就我在战场上了
now I'm on a battlefield,
和肖恩的阿姨一起厮杀这些噬魂者
killing all these Soul Suckers with Shaun's aunty,
一位会神奇武功的女神
who's this awesome, magical kung fu goddess.
我还在守护着伟大的护国公
And I'm hanging on to The Great Protector
和我妹妹一起
with my sister at this point,
努力不被超级噬魂者吃掉
trying not to get eaten by the Mega Soul Sucker.
那超级噬魂者真是个讨厌的贱人
Oh, the Mega Soul Sucker was such a nasty bitch.
是的 它想要吃掉我们龙的灵魂
Yeah. It was trying to eat our dragon's soul.
这样它就可以
Which would have allowed it
毁灭整个宇宙
to destroy the entire universe.
是的
Yeah.
我只剩下一个箭头了
I only had one arrow left,
我脑海中所能听到的
and all I could hear in the back of my mind
我妈妈的声音在说
was my mom's voice saying,
“快射箭 你这个小混蛋!”
"Just take the shot, you little mooch!"
所以 我瞄准那噬魂者的喉咙
And so, I aimed right for the Sucker's throat
箭飞出去了  直击要害
and I let her fly.   She hit it dead on.
然后肖恩用了十环
And then Shaun used the Ten Rings
使出了龟派气功！
to do this crazy Kamehameha fireball
瞬间把它炸掉了
that exploded the thing...
是他拯救了世界
...and he saved the world.
是啊 那天我们失去了一些好人…
Yeah, we, uh, lost some good people that day...
但是我们成功了
but we made it.
我们成功了
We made it.
你们嘲讽完我了吗
Are you done mocking me?
哦,不 我们不是在嘲讽你
Oh, no. We're not mocking you.
那你妹妹在哪里?
So where is this sister of yours?
她回到了我爸的地盘
She's back at my dad's compound,
去停掉他的行动了
shutting down his operations.
是啊 在过去的一千年里
Yeah, his dad was the head of The Ten Rings
他爸爸是十环军队的头儿
for the past thousand years.
两周前 你还在停车收小费
Two weeks ago, you were parking cars for tips,
而你现在想让我相信你刚从噬魂者
and you want me to believe you're now saving the world
手里拯救了世界?
from soul sucking monsters?
我知道你们想让我收回
I know, you're trying to get me back
我上次说的话 但我是不会道歉的
for what I said last time, but I'm not gonna apologise...
我只是作为你们的朋友 说了句实话
...for speaking the truth as a friend.
我是真心的 事实上 我也就是那么想的
I really meant what I said, and, in fact, I actually think
你们现在所做的一切进一步证明了我的观点
this whole bit you're doing just further proves my point.
你们显然…
You guys are obviously...
怎么了？尚气
What?   Shang Chi.
尚气
Shang Chi.
嗯…在这里
Uh... Here.
还活着呢
Present.
我是王
My name is Wong.
我知道 先生 我是你的超级粉丝…
Yeah, I know, sir. I'm a huge fan...
十环在你手上吗？
Do you have the rings?
嗯…是的,是的
Uh... Yeah, yes.
好 走吧 我们有很多话要谈
Good. Let's go, we have a lot to talk about.
你也一样
You too.
我也是吗?
Me too?
我觉得我们应该… 是的
I think we should...   Yeah.
我们得走了 是的
Uh, we gotta go.   Yeah.
我知道这很疯狂 但我会给你发短信
I know this is, like, crazy, but I'm gonna text you,
我们再来一次 很高兴见到你 约翰
and we'll do this again. Nice to see you, John.
我会转钱给你的
I'll Venmo you for the...
你是在庆祝国庆日
You was crusin' with your top down Fourth of July
我沿着街区走我们在交通灯处被抓住了
I was movin' down the block We got caught at the light
我从窗户往外射击
Out my window I was shooting my shot
看天空中的烟花
Watching fireworks in the sky
我要开始了 我要开始了
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
我现在就叫它
I'm calling it now
你会找到爱我的
You'll find love with me somehow
是的 我现在是这么叫的
Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
夏天我们把顶篷放下来吸收阳光
In the summers we let the top down Soak up the light
我想要的只是锁定我一生的挚爱
All I wanted was just to lock down the love of my life
就像午夜开车一样简单
Nice and simple like a midnight drive
看天空中的烟花
Watching fireworks in the sky
我要开始了 我要开始了
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
我现在就叫它
I'm calling it now
你会找到爱我的
You'll find love with me somehow
是的 我现在是这么叫的
Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
噢,噢,噢
Ooh, ooh, ooh
每一行 每一个字每一个名词和动词都可以定义你
Every line, every word every noun and verb can define you
噢,噢,噢
Ooh, ooh, ooh
你很害羞 但你让我靠边停车
You were shy but you told me to pull over
现在我就在你身后
And now I'm right behind you
我们走得有点快 但感觉是对的
We was movin' kinda fast but the feeling was right
我们应该去内华达今晚结婚
We should cruise up to Nevada Get married tonight
只要有你在我的生命里 生活就很简单
Life is simple as long as you're in my life
看天空中的烟花
Watching fireworks in the sky
我要开始了 我要开始了
I'm calling it now I'm calling it now
我现在就叫它
I'm calling it now
你会找到爱我的
You'll find love with me somehow
是的 我现在是这么叫的
Yes, somehow I'm calling it now
嗯
Hmm.
跟我们法典里的任何文物都不匹配
They don't match any artefacts from our codex.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
嗯 我不确定
Mm, I'm not sure.
它们不是振金 难道是齐塔瑞人的？
They're not vibranium. Chitauri?
这跟我见过的其他外星科技一点也不像
Not like any alien tech I've seen.
你爸爸带在身上多久了
How long did your dad have them
才把他交到你手里的？
before he gave them to you?
嗯…
Um...
大约一千年？
About a thousand years.
他们的热致发光显示
Their thermoluminescence indicates
它们存在的时间比那还久
they're older than that.
久多了
By a lot.
你第一次用十环的时候
The first time you used the rings,
我们在卡玛泰姬感受到了
we felt it in Kamar Taj.
这是什么?
What is it?
一个信标
A beacon.
他们在传递信息
They're sending a message.
传到哪的信息?
A message to where?
我很抱歉 我得处理一下这件事
I'm so sorry. I have to deal with this.
你可以向布鲁斯要我的电话号码
You can get my number from Bruce.
很高兴见到你
It was so nice to meet you.
好吧,我……我并没有她的电话号码
Yeah, I... I don't have her number.
她……她经常这样
She... She does this a lot.
伙计们,注意安全
Guys, stay safe.
欢迎来到马戏团
Welcome to the circus.
我知道你一时难以接受
I know this is a lot to take in,
但你得开始习惯了
but you're gonna have to start getting used to that.
从现在开始 你们的人生轨迹
From now on, the trajectory of your lives
将会是你们从未经历过的
will be like nothing you've ever experienced before.
再也没有回头路了
And there's no going back.
你们俩都还有很长一段路要走
You both have a long journey ahead of you.
回家 休息一下
Go home, get some rest.
好主意
Yeah. That's a good idea.
是啊 也许我们应该这么做
Yeah. Yeah, we probably should do that.
还是说……
Or...
欢迎光临加州旅馆
Welcome to the Hotel California
多么可爱的地方 多么可爱的地方
Such a lovely place   Such a lovely place
多么可爱的脸 多么可爱的脸
Such a lovely face   Such a lovely face
加州旅馆有足够的房间
Plenty of room at the Hotel California
一年中的任何时候 一年中的任何时候
Any time of year   Any time of year
你可以在这里找到它
You can find it here
她的思想被蒂凡尼扭曲了
Her mind is Tiffany twisted
她开着奔驰车
She got the Mercedes bends, uh
她有很多漂亮的男孩 她称之为朋友
She got a lot of pretty, pretty boys she calls friends
他们如何在院子里跳舞 夏天的甜汗
How they dance in the courtyard, sweet summer sweat
有些舞是为了回忆 有些舞是为了忘记
Some dance to remember, some dance to forget
于是我叫来船长"请给我拿酒来"
So I called up the Captain "Please bring me my wine"
他说"我们这里从1969年起就没有这种酒了"
He said, "We haven't had that spirit here since 1969"
那些声音仍然从远处传来
And still those voices are calling from far away
半夜把你吵醒
Wake you up in the middle of the night
只听他们说
Just to hear them say
欢迎光临加州旅馆
Welcome to the Hotel California
多么可爱的地方 多么可爱的地方
Such a lovely place   Such a lovely place
多么可爱的脸
Such a lovely face
他们在加州旅馆尽情狂欢
They livin' it up at the Hotel California
真是个惊喜 真是个惊喜
What a nice surprise   What a nice surprise
使你有了来到这里堕落的借口
Bring your alibis
他们还在等着
They're waiting.
开始吧
Let's get started.
我们有很多事情要做
We have a lot of work to do.